Experienced and passionate fullstack software engineer



shane@mediashane.com

1.801.410.3048

mediashane.com

linkedin.com/in/mediashane

github.com/mediashane

About

I'm an experienced engineer with a proven trackrecord of success who's shipped projects and products for some of the biggest brands and companies in the world. Web, mobile and desktop - I work in all environments with creativity, flexibility and reliability.

I'm capable of leading teams, working independently, or fitting in. Years of agency and freelance experience have conditioned me to adapt to and work with just about any tech, team or timeline.

I thrive in creative and friendly environments that give space for experimentation, independent thought and supportive collaboration.

Skills

- JavaScript (ES6+), TypeScript, HTML5, CSS3
- React.js, React Native, Vue.js, Electron.js
- Redux, Zustand, Context API
- Node.js, Express.js, Docker
- Next.is, Vercel, Vite, Webpack
- Tailwind, Radix, Material UI, Responsive Design
- SASS, LESS, SCSS

- PostgresSQL, NoSQL, SQL, MySQL, SQLite, MongoDB
- Supabase, Firebase, Serverless Architecture
- Chrome browser extension development
- GraphQL, RESTful APIs
- Google Cloud, AWS
- Git, Github, Gitlab
- Agile and Scrum Methodologies

Experience

Senior Lead Software Engineer, Koalition Interactive

2018 - Present | Remote, USA

- Shipped 20 projects and products for 26 clients using 23 different technologies
- Develop a wide variety of software across tech stacks and environments for mobile, web and desktop
- Lead teams and mentor developers to encourage growth, confidence and productivity
- Architect solutions for all aspects of development: frontend, backend, databases, servers and APIs

Web, iOS, and Android Engineer, MediaShane

2014 - 2018 | Remote, USA

Build web and mobile apps using React, React Native, Node and modern Javascript

Web Developer, Attract/Interact

2016 - 2018 | Bend, OR

Customize and build additional functionality for WordPress websites and themes

Web Developer and Associate Producer, KUED Channel 7

2013 - 2014 | SLC, UT

- Develop the official kued.org website and produce associated digital content
- Research and produce short form documentaries on local social issues

Web Developer and Digital Media Specialist, Salt Lake City Public Library

2007 - 2012 | SLC, UT

- Lead developer and administrator of all things digital (website, intranet, social networks, media content)
- Research and implement new technology trainings, services and programs

Web Developer, Red Butte Garden

2009 | SLC, UT

Developed and maintained the official redbuttegarden.org

Database Administrator, Utah Museum of Fine Arts

2004 - 2005 | SLC, UT

• Administered fund-raising and membership database

Education